When you encounter animals, do you wonder what they’re thinking?
当你遇到动物时，会不会好奇它们在想什么？
Seeing a newborn lamb or a cute puppy might stir up happy emotions in us, but what are they thinking?
看到刚出生的小羊羔或是可爱的小狗，我们或许会很开心，但它们心里在想些什么呢？
Does the look on their face and how they behave indicate how they’re feeling – or are they feeling nothing at all?
它们的面部表情和行为动作，是否能反映出它们的情绪——还是说，它们根本毫无感觉？
Humans have a complex range of emotions, but it’s hard to tell what’s going on inside the heads of animals, mainly because they can’t verbalise their feelings.
人类拥有复杂多样的情绪，但我们很难揣测动物的内心活动，主要是因为它们无法用语言表达自己的感受。
Perhaps it’s pets we think we understand most – as they are the animals we spend a lot of time with and therefore get to know best.
或许宠物是我们自认为最了解的动物——毕竟我们会花大量时间和它们相处，也因此能最了解它们。
Some of us own dogs because they are good companions, are loyal and seem to connect with us.
有些人养狗，是因为狗狗是很好的伙伴，它们忠诚可靠，而且似乎能与我们产生情感共鸣。
We might even think they love us, although love could just be a human emotion.
我们甚至会觉得狗狗是爱我们的，尽管“爱”可能只是人类才有的一种情感。
Professor Kim Bard, an expert in comparative developmental psychology from the University of Portsmouth, told the BBC: “We have a few studies now that actually show, scientifically… that [some] dogs will respond with empathetic concern when their owner – but not a stranger – pretends to cry.”
朴茨茅斯大学比较发展心理学专家金·巴德教授在接受BBC采访时表示：“目前已有几项研究从科学层面证实……当主人（而非陌生人）假装哭泣时，一些狗狗会表现出共情式的关切。”
The empathetic ability of cats, however, is harder to work out.
不过，猫咪的共情能力则更难被探明。
Other non-domesticated animals might have feelings too.
其他非驯养动物或许也拥有情感。
Giraffes and whales, for example, are known to experience grief when someone in their group dies.
例如，长颈鹿和鲸鱼在群体中有成员离世时，会表现出悲伤的情绪。
Farm animals we often eat, such as cows and chickens, are also believed to experience pain, joy and other emotions.
我们常食用的农场动物，比如牛和鸡，也被认为能感知疼痛、喜悦等多种情绪。
Their wellbeing is now taken into consideration more.
如今，人们也越来越重视这些动物的福祉。
And in the UK, new legislation means all vertebrate animals and crustaceans will be recognised in law as sentient beings.
在英国，一项新法规规定，所有脊椎动物和甲壳类动物都将在法律上被认定为具有感知能力的生物。
It’s believed even tiny creatures like insects might have emotions as well.
人们认为，即便是昆虫这类小型生物，也可能拥有情绪。
Research is beginning to show they experience a wide range of feelings.
相关研究已开始表明，昆虫能体验到丰富多样的感受。
Writing for BBC Future website, Zaria Gorvett says “they can be optimistic, cynical, or frightened, and respond to pain just like any mammal would.”
扎丽娅·戈韦特在为BBC未来频道撰稿时写道：“它们会乐观、会多疑、会感到恐惧，而且和所有哺乳动物一样，它们也会对疼痛做出反应。”
Dr Barbara J King, Emerita Professor of Anthropology at the College of William and Mary, told the BBC: “If we understand the profound depths of emotions animals can feel, this should make us question the existence of zoos and slaughterhouses around the world, and rethink those systems.”
威廉玛丽学院人类学荣誉退休教授芭芭拉·J·金博士在接受BBC采访时表示：“如果我们能明白动物所能感受到的情感是多么深刻，我们就应该对世界各地动物园和屠宰场的存在提出质疑，并重新审视这些体系。”
It does seem all creatures feel emotion, but what is not clear is do they feel the same way as us?
似乎所有生物都拥有情感，但目前尚不清楚的是，它们的情感体验是否和人类完全相同？